EMEHELU RAPHAEL ONWURA

Address: Prince and Princess Estate, Duboyi District, FCT Abuja. | Email: rafaelpascal234@gmail.com

Phone: +234(0) 8164493471

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/raphael-emehelu-20724b13a/

GitHub: https://github.com/rafaelpascal

CAREER SUMMARY

A skilled software developer with over 2 years of experience, I am committed to delivering cost-effective and timely results while working within project specifications. With a strong passion for technology and a keen interest in learning, I am always looking for ways to grow and advance my skills.

SKILLS

- Communication
- Teamwork
- Tech-savvy

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER APPMART INTEGRATED LIMITED

January 2022 – present, FCT, ABUJA

Company Staff Report App

- Built a frontend where users can come to create account and using a Rich Text Editor collect the information of what they did for the week.
- Built a Backend that Accepts users details during sign up and Sign in with full authentication and authorization process, stores their information in Mongo DB database, also can accept and persist the work they did for the week.

Payment option

• Built a Backend where my API makes a call to an external API which then Generates account Detail for a user to make payment with.

VAS Integration

• Using Node JS Mongo DB I was able to integrate to Xpress payment Services, Integrated to their Airtime, Data, Education, Electricity Etc so that the company client can buy airtime, data through them.

Nicetel Admin UI and Backend

 Using React Js, Tailwind CSS I was able to develop an admin UI for admin.nicetel.com.ng, and using Node Js I developed a well-structured, detailed backend service that uses MySQL DB to persist User's Data.

Agrify Mobile App/AdminUI/ Backend

- Using React Native, Tailwind CSS, Typescript I was able to develop a mobile App,
- Using Node JS, MySQL I Was able to develop the backend Service that is connected to the Agrify mobile app and Admin UI.
- Currently Working on the admin UI of Agrify Admin UI.

Skolasuite (School portal)

• Part of the Development Team that developed a School Portal, for the management of a school.

Staff Verification Portal (One ID)

- Part of the Development Team that Developed a Staff Verification Portal for an external Organization.
- Built an Endpoint for the communication of email and SMS messages to multiple users in at once.

Pay handle

• Built the Frontend for the Payment System Using Vue Js.

DATA Upload

• Developed a Backend project that accept an excel file and store in MySQL Database.

Amazon Store Clone (Practical Project)

• Using React Js I was able to develop an amazon store for practical purposes.

Personal Portfolio (Practical Project)

• Using React Native, Tailwind Css I was able to develop some personal portfolio for practical purposes.

SALES EXECUTIVE

APPMART INTEGRATED LIMITED

September 2019 – December 2021, Awka, Anambra State.

- Managed and Trained 30+ Anambra State Internal Revenue Staffs on the use of many revenue App developed by the Appmart Integrated Limited.
- Part of the team that Managed and Trained 30+ Imo State Internal Revenue Staffs on the use of many revenue App developed by the Appmart Integrated Limited.
- Ran multiple stress Test on developed Application.
- Using Excel Spreadsheet to manage and organize payments made through the company system.
- Performed multiple Zoom Training for the company.

ASSISTANT MANAGER.

Aloy Peace Computer Center

January 2013 – January 2014, Anambra State.

- Managing the Company financial records.
- Attending to Customer's.

EDUCATION

FEDERAL POLYTECHNIC OKO.

HND. Computer Science June 2016 | Anambra State GPA 3.41

CONVENANT POLYTECHNIC.

ND. Computer Science September 2014 | Abia State, Aba GPA 3.26

DEVAMPLIFY

Web Development 2020

CODEDAMN

JavaScript Basics Certificate of Completion March 2022

CODEDAMN

Node Js Certificate of Completion May 2022

PIRPLE

JavaScript: ES6 Certificate of Completion May 2022

PIRPLE

Node Js Master Class Certificate of Completion May 2022

• NATIONAL YOUTH SERVICE CORP

2018 | Anambra State

• DIGITAL EXPERIENCE COMMUNICATIONS.

Desktop Publishing 2014 | Anambra State Distinction

CERTIFICATIONS AND LICENSES

• https://drive.google.com/drive/u/0/folders/1QmjN7zr3_ZWZIacvLBkiTnbavxbrI7ZY

REFEREE

• Available on request.